COME ON
Come on!
owareru youni
Running like a fugitive,
isoi de iru
being chased by something.
kawai ta mune ga
Inside my heart is pounding,
kari tateru no sa
my throat dry like it's withering.
dare no tame de naku
For no single one,
dare no mono de naku
to none does belong,
ore tachi no ima ga
this time is ours, right now...
itami hodoki kokoro hodoki kage o hodoki
Unraveling the pain, unraveling our hearts, unraveling shadows.
iki o tsunete hashiri nukero yami o saite
Stifling our breath, reaching for beyond, tearing through the dark.
tatakau koto mo aishi au koto mo
In fighting and in love.
owari wa shinai
To the distant light above,
ON THE WAY
yes, we are on the way!
I WANNA ROCKS mune ni ROCKS
I wanna rock... Rockin' my heart...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Morino Ibiki, proctor for
the first test of the Chunin Exam.
You, from Hidden Sound Village!
No doing as you please
before the Exam!
You want to be failed
at the get go?!
Sorry. It's our first time taking the Exams,
so we flipped out... despite ourselves.
Hmph.This is a good opportunity,
so I'll say this.
There will be no battles,
competitions and the like
without the permission
of the proctors!
And even if you get permission,
actions that could lead to the death
of an opponent will not be permitted.
Any pig that screws with me
will be disqualified immediately.
Got it?!
This Exam looks to be easy!
Now then, we will start
the first test of the Chunin Exam!
Turn in your applications,
take one of these number cards
in exchange,
and sit in the seat
matching that number!
After that, we will hand out
the paper for the written test!
Written...? Paper...?
Paper...
A paper test?!
One Fail Already?
The Extremely Difficult
First Exam
Everyone's seats are all scattered...
What should I do?
He's deflated, deflated...
It's the worst type of test for Naruto...
Naruto-kun...
Oh! You are Hinata...!
Since when have you...?
L-Let's both do our best.
Y-Yeah.
I didn't notice her at all.
Hinata has no presence at all...
There are several important
rules to this first test.
I will take no questions,
so listen well accordingly!
Rules? No questions will be taken...?
First off is the first rule!
You are given ten points
each from the start!
The written test has
ten problems in all!
Each problem is one point.
And, this test is a
point deduction system.
You are deducted one point for
each problem you get wrong!
If you get three wrong,
you'll have seven points!
If I get ten wrong,
I'll have zero points...
The second rule.
Pass or failure will be determined
by the total points of
the three-person teams.
W-Wait a minute!
What do you mean...
total points of the teams?
Shut up!
There's a perfectly
good reason for this!
Shut up and listen!
Reason...?
If you've got it,
here is the most important next rule!
Those who are deemed by
the sentinels
as having committed an act of
cheating or something similar to that...
will have two points deducted
for each act.
— What...?
— Oh!
In other words...
there may be those who will be
dismissed during this test
without waiting for test grading.
This means they're deducting points
from things other
than the written test problems.
Know that those who
commit awkward cheating...
will bring ruin upon yourselves.
I'll check you anytime.
If you aspire to become
a Chunin at all,
know that Shinobi should act
like exemplary Shinobi.
Relax...!
Yes... yes!
Naruto aside,
Sasuke-kun and I are okay!
Even if Naruto gets zero points...
if we cover that...
And, in the case of even one person
on the team getting zero points...
Everyone on that team will fail!
Wha...?!
What did he say...?!
I feel two menacing stares...
Naruto-kun?
By the way, the last problem will
be given forty-five minutes
after the start of the test!
The time for the test is one hour.
Begin!
Could it...
Could it be that,
the fat is really on the fire now...?
Naruto...!
Just don't get zero points!
Naruto isn't getting jitters
from the get go, is he...?
This is bad...
As if!
I know I've cleared many obstacles
like this before...
At times like this, one should
look at all the problems
without feeling pressed
or making a fuss!
And then with utmost effort
I should tackle the problems that look
easy to understand!
Let's see, the first problem...
is a code text, eh...
Excellent, I say!
Next! Next!
Let's see... the second problem...
The parabola B in the diagram illustrates
the greatest possible distance
Enemy Ninja A can throw his Shuriken
from a tree seven meters high...
Predict and answer the Enemy Ninja's
character inferred
from the ellipse this Shuriken forms,
also answer the longest firing range
in battle on flat ground
and explain your basis.
T-This is an... integrated problem based
on predictions
of uncertain conditions and
dynamic energy analysis application...!
There's no way
Naruto can solve this!
I mean...
hardly anyone except me
can solve this problem!
Okay, next!
Next!
These other problems...
are nothing but difficult ones.
I see...
I don't... understand even
one of these problems.
Oh, no, this is bad!
For real! For real!
What should I do?
What should I do? What should I do?
If about ten of all fifty-one teams
are able to pass,
it will be bad if I didn't stretch myself and
get a considerable amount of points.
It's like a system inviting cheating...
I hope Sasuke-kun and Naruto
won't panic and cheat.
It's okay...
Naruto's not that much of an idiot...
I know that...
Don't panic...
For now, all there is to do is to be
very, very cautious...
and cheat without being found out!
No! No! I can't, that's no good,
no good!
I can't tread on such thin ice!
At any rate, this elaborate fuss...
It's like a trick assuming
that we're going to cheat.
They probably check with that paper...
Somebody got nailed.
Cheating deducts two points.
Two-point deduction, huh...
Ordinarily, it'd be failure the moment
the cheating was discovered...
Know that those who
commit awkward cheating
will bring ruin upon themselves.
Shinobi should act like exemplary Shinobi.
I see, so that's how it is, eh.
This wasn't just an achievement test!
The real aim was...
a test to see the ability
for intensive information collection
with the full use of deception
and concealment techniques.
"Shinobi should read
"the double bluff," eh...
In other words, the true intention
of the proctor is...
if you're going to cheat,
not "awkward cheating,"
but "like exemplary Shinobi",
don't get caught.
Viewed in this light, the extra-ordinariness
of the point deduction system,
the lenience of only deducting two points
for each discovery of cheating makes sense.
In other words,
what's being tested here is how
we can gather the correct answers
without having our cheating detected
by the proctors or
by the one being cheated on.
Realize it quick, Naruto!
It'll turn into a fatal mistake!
Realize it!
This is bad.
If the purpose of this test is seeing
the ability to gather information...
then there should be someone
in this classroom somewhere...
who knows the answers
to the problems!
So Gaara has also started, eh...
Hmph... I'm counting on you, Crow.
Yahoo, good boy, Akamaru!
Next is problem four!
Judging from this rhythm...
The stroke order...
and the number of strokes...
I see.
Okay! Please tell me.
Eight, huh.
Lee, if you can see it,
wear your headband!
Time is rapidly going by!
Oh, man! I'm afraid all there
is to do is cheat...
But, if I'm discovered,
it'll be trouble for Sakura-chan
and Sasuke.
On the other hand,
if I get zero points...
Sakura-chan and Sasuke will be
my companions in failure.
Naruto-kun...
I'll show you... my test.
Huh...?
What is Hinata saying...?
W-Why would she do
such a thing for me?
Could it be... some kind of trickery?
But Hinata is not one to do
something like that...
No... But she might've been coaxed into
attempting to trap me by Kiba and others...
Hinata, let me ask you one thing!
Huh?!
Why would you show me?
Uh... uh... actually...
I... I...
I don't want you, Naruto-kun...
to leave at this stage...
Y-You see...
the nine of us are the only rookies...
and I have many anxieties about
what's to come, so!
I get it now! I was kind of
strangely suspicious of you!
Anyhow! This is crazy lucky!
Thank goodness I'm next to Hinata...
W-What was that?
I was about to turn...
W-What was that for, sir?!
You made five mistakes. You fail!
N-No way...
His two buddies, both of you get out
of the classroom, right now.
#23 fails!
#43 and #27 fail!
No!
Hey, hey! Do you have proof that
I cheated five whole times?!
Really, are you guys properly checking
this number of people...?
Listen up...
Even among us Chunin, we're elite
who were selected for this Exam.
We don't overlook you blinking once...
In a matter of speaking,
this strength is the proof.
Naruto-kun...?
Hurry... Look...
Hinata... You don't get it, do you?
What...?
An awesome ninja like me
won't cheat.
N-Naruto-kun.
B-But...
Also, if something went wrong,
you'd be in a hot spot for
helping me cheat, right?!
What?!
Naruto-kun...
I'm... sorry...
I-I did something uncalled for...
Nah, it's okay.
I... went and acted big.
What should I do?
I'm extremely stupid.
Byakugan!
Sharingan!
I'll copy all his movements!
My hand is moving fluently...
I hit the jackpot straight away
with this guy.
Sakura, it looks like you're done, eh.
I'm acknowledging that your smarts
and the width of your forehead
are exceptional.
So you should thank me.
Thank me for getting to be
the target for this Jutsu.
Ninja Art, Mind Transfer Jutsu!
So Ino... started using that Jutsu...
There's no countering that spell of Ino's...
Sakura, I let myself move
into your mind for just a little bit.
I have to memorize the answers quick.
I've got to pass these answers
to Shikamaru and Choji.
#59! Fails!
#33! #9!
This is the thirteenth group to fail.
#41 fails.
#35, #62 fails!
No way!
That brat...
He coolly proceeds through this
ruckus without moving an eyelash.
Very well done considering he's new.
The optic nerves are connected...
The third eye... open!
Ugh! There's dirt in my eye...
Damn it...!
Excuse me.
What is it?
I need to go to the bathroom...
We will accompany you
to the bathroom.
I see...
Anyhow... the proctors are
nothing so special!
They don't realize that the proctors
have increased by one...
Eh, don't you think so...
Crow...?
Forty minutes have passed
since the test started...
Twenty minutes left... huh...
Since it's come to this,
it's the last problem to be given
forty-five minutes after the start of the test.
All there is to do is bet on this.
Cultivate your hunger before you idealize.
Motivate your anger to make them all realize.
Climbing the mountain, never coming down.
Break into the contents, never falling down.
My knee is still shaking, like I was twelve.
Sneaking out of the classroom, by the back door.
A man railed at me twice though, but I didn't care.
Waiting is wasting for people like me.
Don't try to look so wise.
Don't cry 'cause you're so right.
Don't dry with fakes or fears,
'Cause you will hate yourself in the end.
Don't try to look so wise.
Don't cry 'cause you're so right.
Don't dry with fakes or fears,
'Cause you will hate yourself in the end.
Don't try to look so wise.
Don't cry 'cause you're so right.
Don't dry...
Even if I take it, I'm a Genin for life
once I get it wrong?!
(Really? Really? Really?)
If I don't take it, I'll fail with
my comrades immediately?
(No way, no way, no way.)
The hopeless rule for problem ten!
(Not good, not good, not good.)
No way can I choose which one!
(What to do, do, do, do.)
This is seriously, seriously bad!
(Bad, bad, bad, bad.)
Next episode:
"An off-the-cuff match! The 10th Question That We Must Hold Out On."